happy New Year and welcome to concept
and coding this is Shan and today in
spring board we are going to do very
important topic like you can call it
Association types or mappings like one
to one mapping one to many many to many
Etc so let's start without wasting any
time with one to one unidirectional okay
so one entity let's say a references
only one instance of another
entity okay but reference exist only in
One Direction that is from parent to
child okay that's why one to one
unidirectional only one-sided Direction
so for example user one user can have
only one
address so here we can have a reference
user can have a reference of address and
it is like only one-sided from user you
can get the address
details but from address you can't get
the user Detail no so reference only
exist at the one side from user to
address and there is one to one one user
one address that's all so similar kind
of example I have shown here so I have
created one entity with the table name
like user undor detail okay so this is
my entity user details it has certain
Fields like primary key ID name phone
and I also wanted to have a reference of
user address okay so user address I have
created another
entity but I wanted to store it a
reference like a foreign key so that's
why I use it at theate one 121
annotation casket equals to casket type
doall so don't worry about this casket
type we will discuss in depth but first
focus on this at theate one 121
annotation so what this atate one 121
annotation is doing is inside this user
detail or you can say that user unor
detail table it creates one foreign key
okay and that foreign key is like this
ID user address ID okay so from user
details you can access user address but
it's only one way that's why it is known
as one to one
unidirectional okay so user address has
certain like what is the street city
state country PIN code and some unique
uh ID which I called a primary key okay
and it's a generation Ty identity you
already know that automatically it will
increment okay so this is how going to
table look like in the user detail table
you will see that all these columns will
be there so ID name phone apart from
that one foreign key okay and uh it
would be user address so by default see
we haven't give any name for this uh
foreign key right so hibernate will
create like field name whatever the
field name underscore ID so user uncore
addressor ID it will create so this is a
foreign key and foreign key of
this okay for the user
address okay this
ID is equivalent to user uncore
addressor ID and this is a foreign key
in this table user uncore detail
table okay so by default hibernate
choose the foreign key name as field
undor Name ID so I I already told you if
you don't give any name here of this uh
reference how this user uncore addressor
ID
came and it chooses the primary key of
other table so here also if you see I
only tell hey one to one mapping and
this
entity so it automatically chooses the
primary
key okay as the reference for a foreign
key here in this
table but if you need a more control
over it we can use at theate join column
annotation okay you don't want hibernate
to choose the name for you and also you
don't want like uh you want to
specifically mention by yourself what
key you want to create as a foreign key
okay so what you can do is you can use
here like one to one casket type don't
worry worry about it so but one to one
annotation so this will tell that in
this entity or in this table user uncore
details table there will be one foreign
key of
this entity now what is the name of that
foreign key so now we are specifically
mentioning at theate join column what is
the name I want addressor ID okay to be
shown in the table
so here if you see addressor ID is
coming not user _ addressor ID also I am
here specifically mentioning that what
primary key col what foreign key column
is pointing to in the other entity so ID
so it is specifically I'm mentioning
this one but here you can have one
question that hey what about the
composite key when we have more than uh
two columns then how hnet by default
will choose that what to provide then it
will not work by default you have to
provide using adate join column that in
case of composite key so I will show you
how Okay so the same question comes to
our mind what about the composite key
how to reference it we need to use at
theate join
columns okay so from the previous video
you already know how to create a
composite key so now let's say in the
user address
entity
okay I want these two columns Street and
pin code to be considered as a composite
key let's say for example these two
combining is a unique field okay so I
I'm using this Approach at theate
embeddable so I created a new class user
address composite key and I added all
the fields with switch together creating
a composite key okay now in the user
address I am using at theate embedded ID
and choosing
the creating an object of this right and
this is I'm calling it as an ID and all
the other fields of the user address
okay so user address would uh look like
like a normal City Country pin code
State Street all the fields like uh
Street pin code city state country and
you can check that it is considered as a
inside this your
address this table address this is your
composite key okay now we have a
composite key now I want to create one
to
one
unidirectional mapping okay so from user
details so I'm creating another entity
user details it has certain its own
field like primary key name phone now I
want to create a foreign key or you can
say that it should have a reference to
user address okay but now it has
composite key how I would create it okay
so first of all I have added like
defined the field user address this
one now I have annotated with at the1
121 this will tell that to the jpa that
this would
this table contains a foreign key okay
uh for this
entity now what what should be the name
and what should be the column or you can
say that the ID this foreign key points
to so I am using at theate join columns
okay in case of composite key we have to
provide all the
IDs composite IDs here let's say now
this is an array right so inside join
columns like this you have to
provide all the composite Keys like at
theate join column name equals to I give
addressor Street reference column name
Street this
one add another at theate join column
address pin code this is the name which
I wanted okay and what is the reference
column name pin code this one so all the
fields of the composite key I need to
mention like this by default hiet don't
know or jpa don't know what key it has
to use in case of composite key you have
to specifically mention like this so now
here if you see the user undor detailed
table how it going to look like ID this
one name phone it has name phone and
then addressor Street and address _ pin
code address uncore Street and addressor
pin code so address in the user detail
table address PIN code and
street this is a foreign
key okay and what columns it pointing to
this pin code is pointing to this
one and this street is pointing to this
one okay this is what we
pointed okay now before we proceed
further with other mappings like one to
one bir directional many to one there
are few things which we have to see
like what is casket type now we have
seen that when we are providing and
mapping like at the rate 1 to one casket
equals to casket type. all what it is
man like why we are using this what's
the purpose of
it so let's see that what all values it
can take first casket type so casket
type can have six values all persist
merge remove refresh and
detach so without casket type any
operation on parent do not affect child
entity managing child entities
explicitly can be error prone so
consider this you have a parent
entity and it has one child entity
I can say that the life of a child here
depends on the parent or you can say
that a existence of a child entity
depends on a parent entity if parent
entity is destroyed child entity should
also get destroyed okay if parent entity
is created child entity is also be
created if parent entity updated if
required if there is any update child
entity should also get updated okay so
we can say that the whenever a use ISE
where child entity existent depend upon
the parent entity this casket type can
help us with that in managing it if they
are
not like if they are independent like if
you are deleting parent but child entity
is not deleted say it could be an error
prone right when we are saying one time
that child entity existing is depend on
parent only for example a school and
room
so here room existing is on school if a
school destroyed room is also destroyed
right so there is no way where like a
school is finished then you have still
have school rooms available that's just
a use
case so casket help in managing that any
operation on
parent right so this is without casket
type with casket type any operation or
parent affect child entity also
so let's say that first casket type is
persist as the name clearly says that
persist means inserting so inserting the
user entity user here it is our
parent so inserting the parent entity
automatically Pur this Associated user
address entity data which is you can say
that
child so if you are inserting the parent
entity automatically its Associated
child entity get inserted two so here in
this use case here if you
see very basic one to one unit
directional only I have a user
details uh so it has certain Fields I am
creating a foreign key here one to one
annotation and I'm just specifically
wanted to give the name so atate join
column address ID is a foreign key name
and what column it should point to other
entities this ID
okay now here I have given casket equals
to casket type.
persist okay so means whenever you are
inserting this
table user address will also get
inserted it's child because this is this
child right user address so that will
also get inserted so now here if you see
very simple example this is One
controller class of a user
details okay so I'm
inserting just calling the save user so
this is the service class and service
class ultimately calling repository
nothing difference like we have already
seen this before so now here I'm trying
to do an insert so I'm calling a post
API this post API and I'm passing this
body so in this body it is accepting
user details so this uh user details it
is accepting so name phone so here I'm
providing name
phone and here inside this user address
object Street city state country pin
code I have provided the body now when I
invoke this okay It ultimately calls
save Okay now what's the response I got
here if you see the response I got an
ID okay and here inside this user
address I also got the ID like this I'm
getting a response so means a row has
been created in the the user detail
table and also in the user address table
also
see Bangalore Karnataka 123 so see all
data got created in both the table so
that's what why because of purs even
though I am calling a save on user
details but still it goes ahead and
updated its child entity
too that's why CET type. purus
does similarly casket type. merge works
on the update updating the user entity
automatically updates his Associated
child user address
entity so for example let's first see
what happen if you use only P persist
casket type and try to update it okay
I'm not using merge for now only
persist so this is the controller class
this is the post this is the put okay in
the user details it will call the
update and here it's a very simple right
uh first based on the ID I will see if
data is present if data is present I
will update it with this new object
which is
coming okay so here you might be saying
that hey for insert also we are calling
save and for update also we are calling
save as I already if you can recall from
the previous video
I have already mentioned that in this
user
patch in the body you will also pass ID
field right or whatever the primary key
so internally it has the logic that if
it's not a new entity means ID primary
key is present instead of inserting it
goes for updation so that's logic is
internally there and I've already
explained that one okay so this is very
basic class which we already know
now what exactly we wanted to test here
is first we are trying to do an insert
operation so insert operation is very
very similar like what we were doing we
are trying to this is my body and I'm
trying to insert name phone number of
the user and also I'm providing the user
address
object so you as you can see properly
got inserted ID here got created and
also for the user address ID got created
properly
created okay so till now we know that
persist helps that caset Ty persist but
now what happen if I do merge second now
I'm trying to do
update so here if you see now I'm
calling a put API okay I'm trying to
update this one user one this
one now here if you see this is the
object I am passing okay so I am also
passing ID because so that it can
internally go for update operation not
insert so for id1 the name I am updating
to XY zore updated but also if you see
user address I am also Chang the city
from Bangalore to bangaluru I change
it but now here if you see the response
what happening the name got properly
updated but in the user address the city
got changed no it didn't
why because of this
purist okay so purist only take care of
insertion but we have to use for
updation we have to use merge because
for updation it will make sure that any
update happening on user entity if there
is any update happening on the child
entity that should automatically get
updated
to so now if I change it that yes
persist also wanted and merge also I
wanted so like this you can give add
theate one 121 on this user detail and
in the casket equals to in this kind of
an array you can provide all whatever
the casket we wanted so let's say I
wanted persist and merge okay now what
happen is so insert properly happen now
in update I am again trying the same two
things I'm trying to update one is in
the user and one is under the user
address now here if you see both get
updated properly
so it's name city name also changed and
the username also got changed here in
the user detail
table okay so cascet happen properly
from parent to
child similarly I think by now you can
already know that what remove would be
doing deleting the user entity
automatically delete its Associated user
address or you can say that child entity
so here I'm creating one delete mapping
okay whatever the ID comes I am just
calling this
service to delete it that's
all I am calling one to one mapping here
in the user details which has which is a
foreign key holding a foreign key and
here I also appending remove I want purs
I want merge and I also want remove
capability so let's say that I first do
an insert properly inserted now if I'm
doing delete operation here if you
see I am calling delete
operation this I'm creating it's 204 no
content properly got deleted because I
am returning this no content so properly
got deleted and if you check the table
there is no
row okay so even though I am calling
delete operation on user detail parent
here if you see I'm calling delete user
okay from ID
I am calling delete by ID on user
details repository but again still it
able to delete the user address table
also because of casket type
remove similarly there are two more
caset type refresh and detach Which is
less frequently used okay both are very
less frequently used but let me again
tell you uh just for reference purpose
but hardly we use it so here if you
notice right whenever internally we call
save you already know about entity
manager I have already explain entity
manager in depth during first level
caching right so entity manager has
multiple method like
persist okay so even though let's say
that from user repository when you're
calling do save internally save what it
is using is entity manager object only
and it's called it Pur method similarly
entity manager has multiple method and
one of them method is called
refresh okay so what refresh does is you
know that entity manager holds
persistence context persistence context
help in first level caching okay so when
you invoke this refresh method it bypass
the persistence context and entity
manager directly query the
DB that's what it is used refresh okay
so here if you
see when you do casket type.
refresh what we what we have to do
here when we use casket type. refresh we
tell jpa to not only read parent entity
from DB but it's Associated child entity
too okay so see in this case okay this
is user detail parent and This Is Us
user address this is a foreign key I'm
creating one to one but casket type I'm
putting refresh what does it mean that
internally whenever let's say hibernate
generally we never do entity manager.
refresh okay I've never seen such use
case but let's say in some point of time
hnet wanted to directly hit DB instead
of first level caching and internally it
might be calling refresh for on user
detail entity because it want user
detail to read directly from DB not from
persistence
context so this casket type refresh make
sure that even the user address is
directly read from DB not from the
persistence
context so you got that point so this is
to uh generally refresh method is to
bypass the persistence context first
level caching and this casket type makes
sure that you bypass for your child
Associated child tables
also similarly casket type.
detach entity manager has one more
method called detach like
persist like refresh similarly detach
you know that I have already explained
in the previous videos the life cycle
life cycle of an
entity who manage it you can uh know
that
like persistence context like holds the
life cycle of an entity till the entity
is in persistence context it holds its
life cycle
like any update insertion deletion
updation okay but if you want to detach
it
okay means jpa is not managing the life
cycle now if you want to detach it you
call the detach
method
okay
so when we use casket type. detach we
tell jpa to not only detach parent
entity but it's Associated child
entities
to okay that's what only its purpose
generally we never use this casket type
but just for
reference also we never use detach
method also internally hibernate might
be using it like for what purpose we
don't know when but let's say in any use
case it want to because to save the
memory or whatever the use case it want
to remove the object or entity from the
persistence context it don't want to
manage it okay so what it do it do
detach and this casket time make sure
that you detach its child entities
too
okay and the last one is that casket
type do all so instead of using like in
an array uh comma casket type do refresh
comma we can simply use casket type. all
means we want all the casket type
capability purist merge remove refresh
and
detach
okay okay so one question should have
come to your mind by now we saw insert
update remove operation okay casket
type okay when insert is happening
because of this casket type child table
also get inserted when update is
happening on parent because of the
casket type merge child table also get
updated similarly for remove on the
parent casket type child got also
removed but what about get we haven't
discussed
it so during get means reading the
entity so does child entities always get
loaded with parent entity
because if you are trying to fetch
parent entity like user
details does user
address will always get
loaded answer is yes or we can or we
cannot it depends whatever use case so
there are two type of loading eager
loading and lazy
loading so eager loading means
Associated entity like child entity is
loaded immediately Ely along with the
parent whenever you do a get call on the
parent child entity is also loaded
immediately and if you see for one to
one and many to one this is the default
mapping so here if you see one to one
annotation what is the fetch default
type is eager similarly for many to one
if you see it functional interface what
is the F Type default is eager
similarly for lazy loading means
Associated entities not loaded
immediately only loaded when explicitly
exist like when we call let's say for
example I am calling user detail get
user address so here I'm trying to
access it so it make another select
query okay so here if you see it is
default for one to many and many to many
like for if you see one to many what
what is the default F Type lazy
similarly for many to many what is the
default F type is again
lazy so in
short if you are using Eagle
loading and you are quering the parent
entity generally whatever the select
query it will make select it will make
with left
join okay you like select your parent
entity left
join your child entity
always but if you're using lazy loading
so first it will do only select query on
parent
entity okay and now on demand if your
code internally doing trying to access
access the child entity here user
address is my child right if your parent
is trying to access the child then it
make another select
query with left
join okay with parent and uh your child
then it make another left another select
query with left join it f the data and
then
return
okay and another things comes to mind
that hey why for one 12 one it's uh F
type is eager why for many to one F type
is eager and why many to many and one to
many it's lazy so see this is my
understanding whenever like one to one
many to one means
this parent have only one child only one
child so jpa do an assumption that since
there is only one child entity so
possibly it might be required while
accessing parent and since it's a one so
it might not be a much impact on the
performance but when we have like one
two
many many too many means many Childs how
many we don't know do we do do parent
require all the Childs okay so here jpa
don't know that so that's why it uses
default lazy based on the demand it
might load it sometime based on the
demand if I do a left join maybe I will
just filter out whatever the child R I
wanted maybe not if there are so many
things I just only want two Childs I can
f those with the query
Okay so
so we can control this Behavior yes we
can control like if I want So currently
this is the default but what if I want
to control that yes for one to one also
I want lazy for one to many also I want
eager like I want to control on my way
can we do that yes we can do that easily
so here if you see this is the entity
very basic entity like what we are
seeing parent right user user detail is
my parent this is its Fields this is the
foreign key which I am
creating okay this is the name of the
foreign key and this is the column uh
for in this entity which is going to be
Associated and here I am using one to
one casket equals to all you already
know now here I'm putting fetch equals
to fetch type do lazy so even for one to
one default is eager now I overriding it
with lazy
so now this fetch type I am overriding
it fetch field I'm overriding it okay so
now if you can try testing this
code let's try testing this code first
do an insert operation so
here I am calling a post operation on
the user so it got properly
inserted okay so I have provided name
phone number for the user and also the
address now here if you see user detail
also get properly populated I got the ID
similarly user address details also got
properly populated I got the
ID okay so insert happened properly both
the tables got inserted user detail
table and user address table both got
populated now I am doing a get
operation okay I am trying this API get
API and I'm trying to fetch this user
which is created
this user which is
created now what my expectation is first
my expectation is that only this data
will come ID name and phone this user
address won't come because I have put
lazy and at nowhere in the code I am
here just I am doing find by in the get
call I'm just doing find by ID and
nowhere in the code I am doing like user
detail do user address so it should not
get loaded
so what output I seeing internal
error
failure now this is question why in why
failure so here what happening
is get operation failed because of
loading user address lazily now since we
are put a Laz lazy on the user address
right foreign key part so during
response building so it has properly
during get call it has properly created
the select query it has properly made
the select
query okay and it fetch only the user
details it has fetch only the user
details now it is creating a response
now this response doesn't have user data
user address data and during response
serialization Jackson got failed it
don't know how to serialize this data
user address since that it is
missing okay so here if you see
serialization got failed which is by
Jackson okay so Jackson doesn't know how
to serialize the data like because user
address data is not even present and you
know that why it is not present because
we have specifically mentioned lazy so
that's
why it might have internally hit a
select
query select query on
parent table that is user undor detailed
table so it doesn't make a left join and
user address details is not even
fetch so in this case user data user
address data is missing so during
serialization Jackson fail they don't
know how to serialize
it so how to fix it so before we fix it
one thing should comes to a man then hey
how for insert it worked why there is no
serialization during insert so during
insert
also when I try to insert in the
response I get user plus user address
also how come now because user address I
have put
lazy I have put lazy then how come this
response has come in the insert so now
remember that during insert
operation what we are doing is we are
first creating an object object we are
having
entity user detail entity and user
address entity both the entity we put
into persistence context and then we
insert it into
DB okay now while constructing a
response it tried to F the user detail
and user address entity does it has to
querry the DB no because both the
objects are in memory in the persistence
context in the same call see in the same
insert call we first inserted into the
persistent contact then into the
DB user address table both got inserted
now in the same insert same entity
manager we are using same entity manager
in during the response it tried to fetch
both the object so it will return from
the persistence context only that's why
it's didn't fail during calization
because user address is entity also
filled up properly but in case of when I
make a get call it is creating a new
entity manager so this this persistent
context is not accessible for the new
entity manager so persistent contact
doesn't have uh this two user detail and
user address so it try to access from DB
and in the DB because of this
lazy it make only select query on the
user detail table user address is not
even left joined with it so that's why
during response creation of the get call
Jackson doesn't know how to serialize
the
user address object this one how to
serialize it and that's why it
failed okay so now let's see that how to
resolve that so one way is that use Json
ignore so in
this my foreign key right this is my
fore key here I put Json ignore so Json
ignore what it will do is that Jackson
will not even put it into the response
it will simply ignore
it okay so now here I have used this so
even if you see that now during the get
call I am getting only user details this
user address is
totally
missed even though it is missing because
of lazy
okay there is no serialization issue
because Jason uh jackon saw that a Json
ignore is there so I don't need to
serialize
itself but it will remove the user
address field totally for both lazy and
eager also even if you change it to
eager then also you won't get the user
address now because we are specifically
telling Jackson to ignore
this now what shall we
do so another thing we can do is using
the dto data transfer object this to me
looks more clean and recommended
approach so see those who don't know
what's dto
right data transfer object so here see
this is your controller see this okay
this is your service class and let's say
this is your Repository
and ultimately this is your entity and
this entity looks exactly to your DB so
till
now whenever any response goes out from
DB to repository to service to
controller so we are returning this
entity only okay and this entity is
equivalent to our DB
tables
generally returning the The Entity
itself is not recommended why because
let's say that in your table you
have columns let's
say A B C D E okay and you have this you
don't want outer world to know exactly
what is your column name and what all
fields are
present you only want to return what
client expected you want client to see I
only want this three columns to see this
two is for always for my internal
purpose DN I don't want it to go outside
man and also I don't want a b c exact my
column's name to be seen outside so what
I can do is I can create a
dto let's say this is entity a so I can
create a dto let's say entity a dto so
here I can put only those fields which I
want let's say for a I want to call like
say proxy a for B I can say proxy B some
different name so that outer world
doesn't know what column name I have
okay and here if you see d d and I don't
want outer world to see so I don't have
DN into my
dto so here now from repository to
service and before controller goes out
to The Entity it do
mapping mapping
from your entity to dto you fill the dto
you create a dto object and you fill the
entity you fill these values and then
ultimately return the dto so outer world
only aware of the
dto okay so that's what I'm saying we
can make use of dto to avoid this
serialization
issue okay now you can say that Hey how
so now let's say that I created this dto
user details dto and I said that these
all the fields which I wanted to go out
ID user ID username phone number and
only
address okay now here if you see that my
dto I want address right so now in the
Constructor I am setting this so here
I'm just printing system. out.
println going to to query user address
here now so user address user detail.
getet user address so now you are making
sure that since you need address here
you are invoking the user address
specifically so by our understanding we
know that at this point of time a query
select query would be make with the left
join and user address data would be
fetch okay and after that this got
filled up and once got filled up not
equals to null then whatever the I
wanted to only send the street address
depending what you want you can fill it
up okay so here if you see that this
makes sure that you are aware what you
are doing you are not relying on Jackson
that to catch the issue so now you are
aware that okay in the response I need
to send the
address even though whether I would be
using lazy or eagerly I don't know I am
checking if the get user is address is
not equals to null then I'm setting it
otherwise I'll will put it null so any
some value would be present in my
dto okay and ultimately this dto will go
out and even though it's a lazy you know
that at this point of time a query would
be made and it will always get filled up
okay so here if you see that this is my
parent entity user
detail everything same one to one I am
using F Type lazy okay and this is my
foreign
key okay and I have created just one me
here like whatever the user details
would be present if I call to dto Method
it will ultimately creating a new dto
object which I created for this one
class it's call its Constructor and pass
the this entity and from this one I am
doing actually a mapping so this mapping
I told you right from entity to Dio
that's only I'm doing from The Entity
I'm just filling whatever I
needed and in the
controller in the controller during get
call first I am doing find by ID so it
find by ID ultimately it will return me
the user detail from that user detail
object I'm calling 2 dto so this
one so this dto will create a dto
object and whatever the object is coming
in the entity it will pass this to here
and from this I will fill up whatever I
required now see the behavior calling a
get call on user
one okay so here if you see output I am
getting is ID name phone address this is
my dto which I created
ID name phone and address and address
called filled up yes even though I
created it
lazy why let's see that see the
behavior so first I have done an
insertion right so here I haven't shown
the insertion but that is same so it
inserted into user detail and also in
the user address so I have the data both
present now I am calling this get call
one with the lazy user detail is marked
lazy so here if you
see select quer is made so from I'm
getting a Name ID phone address ID from
this so here if you see no left join is
made on user table user address table
plain select query on the
parent okay so user address data will
not be fetched at at this point of
time so it will ultimately return it now
find by ID done select query made now I
calling to dto so to dto it will go it
will create a user dto object now I am
filling whatever I wanted now it will
print going to query user address here
now so now here it printed going to
query user data here now so here if you
see at this point of time I am trying to
say that user get user address so
because it was lazy now I am trying to
reference it so now one more select
query would be
made so here if you see one more select
query would be made okay so now it is
fetching the user address data for this
foreign
key
like so now it will fet the user address
uh data
and put
it it now it get address would be filled
up
okay so you got the behavior like how we
can avoid the serialization
issue in the dto is much safer I would
say that because you are totally aware
that if you need the child then you have
to call like this so that uh it make one
select query if you don't need it don't
add it so it will not even try to you
will not even try to add it and
ultimately during the dto uh
serialization no issue will come so
means you are creating or updating the
fields of your dto so either would be
null or some value would be
present
okay so now till now what we have seen
is one to one unidirectional
and with this unidirectional I have
already told you what is casket
type okay and
also I have showed you the different
like
uh different Behavior like eager loading
and the lazy
loading now let's see one to one by by
directional so till now what we have
seen is one 12 one
unidirectional
means you have one parent entity it has
a foreign
key which is a child entity and this
foreign key on on this ID primary key on
this table primary key and you can only
access in One Direction parent entity to
child entity and there is no no way to
backtrack so in one to1
bidirectional you can also travel
backward from child to parent but
remember table structure do not even
change both entities hold reference to
each other means user detail has
reference to user address user address
also has a reference to user details
user address also has reference to user
details but that doesn't means that this
is also also has a foreign key of this
no in the bir
directional the this is the child right
the child also has a reference to your
parent but only in object not in DB so
DB structure would still be the same
only one foreign key into the p parent
entity okay but in the object we also
hold a reference from child to parent I
will show you
how so in the B directional there is a
concept called owner side and the
inverse side owner side is generally
known as
your parent side which holds the foreign
key inward size is generally known your
child entity
okay so owner s side holds the foreign
key relationship in a
table if you
see our previous example like similarly
I have created a user detailed entity
table these are its
field now I want a user address as a
foreign key like before I have created
at the one 121 annotation casket type
all you already know what it will do and
specifically I don't rely on hibernate
so I'm just telling hey this is the name
I want for my foreign key and this is
the column on this user address entity
this is the foreign key
selected okay now this is till now I
have uh done
one-sided like unidirectional but in the
bir directional in this entity user
address entity
okay it is all its field now this is
also holds a reference of user details
it is holding a reference of user
details but one difference you will see
that here is in the one to one
annotation like here we all can also use
it here but here I'm telling that hey
map
by map it to this user
address okay
map it to this user address so now in
this case what would happen
is from user DET user address also you
can access user
details like in in Direction reverse
Direction and also it will not create
any foreign key like in this table even
though we are using one to one why
because of this map by field this just
make sure
that only in object Java object right
during your code you can do a back like
backtrack to your
parent okay so we will see an example it
will get clear so here first of all look
at the table the table will look exactly
the same from user detail all its field
and only one foreign Key address ID
which we
give okay and in the user address you
have all its field there is nothing like
a user addressor ID showed up no nothing
okay because of the map
buy so what would
happen but since we have the backward
capability how we can utilize it let's
see that I am creating a controller and
service class for the user address
because I want to test the backward
capability now if you work on this user
address can I go in the backward
Direction okay even though you my user
address doesn't hold any reference of
the user detail how it would be doing it
so here I have created one simple
controller okay for the user address I
am creating
a a get
API and user hyph address / ID and uh
this is my service class user address
service so this is the object name we
can create user address
service okay so this would be user
address service object F uh this is just
a field name uh class object is properly
for the user address service only so it
will invoke this and ultimately it will
call find by ID so this is very basic
but I created for user address now let's
check the behavior first I am calling an
insert operation like before us using
user detail controller API like the
parent one which I showed earlier so I'm
calling this post API and my user detail
object and the user address
okay a row got properly inserted into
the table okay data is inserted into
user address table and in the user
detail table all
fine now I am doing a get API call on
user
address what what is your expectation at
this point of
time my expectation is
that since I am calling on user address
okay what it will do is when it will
fetch it it will fetch ID Street city
state country pin code since I have used
map
by user detail it will create one
query to fetch its detail of
also okay so I would have a user address
detail also plus user details let's see
that will
that so now here if you see oops what it
is you
have user address ID Street city state
country also user detail what we were
expecting but again what happening again
user address again user detail again
user address some infinite recursion
happened what happened this is not the
expectation why it going infinite it
should have a stop right see I'll tell
you what
happened when we hit a get query
here okay as expected first it make a
select query with left
join from user address to user detail on
the here from the user address what is
the column address ID right uh ID and in
the user underscore detail table address
_ ID so it created this select
query and it is
trying
to okay it is trying to fetch
the where is that uh yeah it is trying
to F the user d detail backward from the
user address it is trying to F the user
details by putting a left join left join
on this address ID and this ID okay so
it is doing correctly but then why it
goes to the infinite recursion Loop so
what exactly happen is during
response
construction Jackson is doing
serialization you know that so during
serialization what happen is is Jackson
start serializing user address after
user address is
serialized okay user address is has like
Street city state country pin
code after that it see that okay it
encounter user details object user
detail so now it has to serialize user
detail so it start serializing it user
detail has ID what name and phone after
after that it find in the user detail
also because of
bidirectional here if you see because of
bidirectional user detail also has
reference of user address so Jackson
again goes to user address now again it
goes to serialize Street city state
again then again it's a user detail then
again it goes to this one again parsing
serializing it so that's why it goes
here in the infinite recursion so first
it properly fetching user address then
it was serializing the user detail after
that it I find out user address then
again it started passing uh serializing
it while passing user address again find
user details and goes on and then
ultimately it
failed
so infinite recursion issue is something
which we have to handle if you're going
with B directional mapping very
important okay so how we can handle this
so there are two ways one is by using
atate Json manage reference and Json
back reference
annotation so Json manage reference
annotation we should use only in owing
entity there is no hard and fast rule
but it's recommended that you use this
only on the owing entity owner parent
which holds a foreign key
relationship it tells explicitly Jason
to go ahead and serialize the child
entity similarly like user detail in the
user detail it has name phone number and
also user address so here if I use atate
Json manage
reference I am allowing that he Jackson
you go ahead and serialize it okay
similarly Json back reference is used
used on the child
entity it tell explicitly to not
serialize the parent
entity see this example same thing
bidirectional this is my
parent okay I am holding a foreign key I
am putting at theate column okay this is
and I am putting at theate Json manage
reference means explicitly telling Jason
hey you can go ahead and serialize it
whenever you are serializing user
details and whenever you find user
address you can realize it similarly in
the child
entity okay I have this fields and then
user detail uh it has a back reference
right user details and this is just a
mapping not table it's a b directional I
am putting map by so no foreign key
would be created so it just a map by by
user address this
field okay so here I have put atate Json
back reference means Hey whenever you
find this do not C I
it so now if you call a API on the
parent first I'm calling on the parent
just see that user one not user hyen
address so if you call on the parent so
parent this would be hit so in response
you will also get this because you are
allowing it to serialize it so you saw
in the response user address
also but if you uh make a get call on
the child user hyphen address so means
you will find this data and after that
it identify this then you have told it
hey Json back reference means don't go
don't go and serialize it so here if you
see you don't see user detail
itself but here you can say that hey
Shan when I go from child to parent I
also want here user detailed data only
but with without recursion without
infinite recursion how we can do
that yes we can do that with Json
identity
info so here in this case for every
object we try to give some unique ID and
Jackson will utilize it to make sure
that it's already serialized before or
not so here if you see I am not using
any back reference or manage reference
very uh this is similar to what my by
one 121 B directional so here I have put
at 1 121 this hold my foreign key this
is my child and here I'm putting map by
to this user
address okay so now in this I am not
putting any back reference so but this
is I am using at the entity
level Json identity info annotation so
here we have providing the property and
the field generally we provide is which
is unique so here in this user detail
what field is unique is this so
generally I provide this you can provide
any other field but it should be unique
because this you can say that Jackson
internally use it to make sure that hey
this with this ID user detail is already
constructed serialized or
not okay so consider something to break
the infinity
recursion similarly for user
address I want
certain unique value for the property so
here also I have a ID this is my unique
so I use it here if there is any
something like addressor ID you can put
addressor ID but it should be
unique now if you make a get call so now
let's say I'm making a get call on the
parent first this one so here I got
properly first parent detail and then
user address child
details similarly if I call the address
uh child from child I am doing a get
call do I get a parent now first I got a
child and now here if you see that it
found that hey I have a child Al parent
reference backtrack also so it will make
uh it will able to properly get its
details also but only one time no
infinite recursion why because of this
unique value now Jackson knows
that this one is already passs one time
so I don't have to go keep on going
doing that so stop the recursion
something like that okay so you got it
right how this bidirectional is handled
in one to one B directional using map by
okay and whenever you are making a query
it's uh making a left query by left join
select query and left join on this uh ID
and this address ID
here okay so in the next part we will
see one to many many to one and many to
many and in the last part we will see
custom queries criteria queries and
pagination and sorting after that our
jpa would be totally
completed okay guys if you have any
doubt let me know we can discuss further
bye